Ryan Lassiter

Full-Stack Software Engineer

Phone (252) 531-9401

E-mail ryankylelassiter@gmail.com

Empathic, Intuitive, Earnest, Perceptive, Leader, Mentor, Model, Senior Full-Stack Software Engineer with intimate knowledge and experience using Typescript, Python, GraphQL, SQL, NO-SQL in a variety of frameworks like React, Vue, Node with Express, Django, and Flask, in a variety of environments - from startups to large enterprise applications.

Work History

2023-04 - Current

Full Stack Software Engineer

The Stow Company, Asheville, NC

- Build new features in React/JavaScript/Django/Python for comprehensive web application used to design and price custom closet spaces for commercial and residential clients
- Collaborate with product/design teams in aligning feature work with business priorities
- · Use complex drawing tools leveraging HTML 5 Canvas API to build a CAD-like object-oriented drawing tool

2021-11 - 2023-02

Full Stack Software Engineer

Tackle, Asheville, NC

- Built and maintained robust and fully-automated customer facing onboarding experience to list products across
 big three cloud marketplaces AWS, Microsoft, and Google. Built with the strength and performance to handle
 exponential customer growth.
- Implemented code generation tools to create type safety between our Node.JS/GraphQL services and internal openapi services. Helped reduce entire subsection of uncaught errors involving undefined properties, resulting in huge win for our developers when working with different complex objects across organization.
- Built new service using Node with Express and Typescript to consume new Microsoft Azure Marketplace API. Reduced many touch points for customer journey team as well as automated large parts of onboarding process for customers using Microsoft Azure Marketplace.
- Environment: React, Apollo GraphQL, Node, Python, Flask, Marshmallow, DynamoDB, AWS

2021-06 - 2022-06

Front-End Technical Lead

Gliply, Asheville, NC

- Designed and developed React frontend architecture for "learning community" SaaS platform
- Built and maintained front-end UI library leveraging React and styled-components with CSS variables and semantic HTML
- Designed front-end data structure/API and implementing GraphQL client to handle consuming and mutating data from GraphQL server
- Created workflows for task/user story creation as well as parsing priorities vs backlog using Asana. This
 included subdividing and estimating story/subtask completion.
- Environment: React, Node, Apollo GraphQL, PostgreSQL

2020-08 - 2021-11

Full Stack Software Engineer

Center For Advanced Transportation Technology Lab, College Park, Maryland

- Built, tested, and maintained large-scale data visualization-centric web apps using React/Node/Python
- Led development of OSS prototype for drawing complex sankey diagrams on client using svg
- Environment: React, LeafletJS, D3.js, Node, Python, Django

2020-12 - 2021-08

Software Engineer

Sustainable Agriculture Research And Education, College Park, Maryland

- · Consulted on and developed services using VueJS and PHP
- Built tools for form administration to more easily manage redundant tasks involved with admin work. Helped increase productivity by simplifying complex UI and creating simpler workflows for managing forms as admin
- Environment: VueJS, Wordpress/PHP

2019-07 - 2020-08

Freelance Software Engineer

Self Employed, Asheville, NC

- Consulted and contributed to projects ranging from small businesses to multinational corporations working
 across varying technology stacks to add new value, reduce complexity, and optimize applications with end users
 in mind
- Individual contributor in variety of environments including React, Typescript, Apollo Client and Server, Vue, Gatsby, Headless CMS's, Netlify JAM stack
- Advised on building and maintaining code bases, API integrations, customer engagement/retention using analytics, and more thoughtful UI/UX implementation

2008-06 - 2019-06

Freelance Musician/Producer/Engineer

Self Employed, Asheville, NC

- Maintained self-owned recording studio. Handled all aspects of business client acquisition, project
 management, contracting musicians to accompany artists, production, engineering, client billing, physical asset
 maintenance and acquisition
- Studied intensively at university level to acquire classical performance mastery as well as recording engineering skills

Skills

TypeScript | ReactJS | GraphQL | CSS - Semantic HTML | Node.JS | Python | Django | Flask | VueJS | SQL | PostgreSQL | Dynamo

Education

2004-08 - 2008-05

Bachelor of Science: Music Technology

Appalachian State University - Boone, NC